In this video we demonstrate the composition task and transcription tasks used to compare smartphone typing with speech recognition
In the composition task participants were shown three clipart images
They had to compose a coherent and grammatically correct sentence incorporating those images using a standard smartphone keyboard in one condition
And using speech recognition in another
VO:The grandmother loves receiving presents from her grandchildren
In the transcription task participants were shown a sentence to transcribe with a standard smartphone keyboard in one condition
And using speech recognition in another
VO: The teenagers went to Bruce's house to drink a cup of tea
For each participant half the
transcription sentences came from a common pool across all participants and the other half were exact phrases the participant composed in the
composition task
For additional information and experiment results see the accompanying paper